- 嘿 去吃午饭吧  - 等等
- Hey, ready for lunch?  - Oh, one sec.
那是高重力离心机的传动系统雏形吗?
Is that the prototype drive system for the high-G rover?
不是 Bernadette给我买了个Fitbit腕表
No, Bernadette got me a Fitbit
想要记录我到底做了多少运动
so she can track how much I'm exercising.
谁让她关心你的健康呢
That'll teach her to care about your health.
我等不及要看我英年早逝时 她是什么表情了
I can't wait to see the look on her face when I die young.
你上次真正运动是什么时候?
When was the last actual exercise you got?
就前几天
The other day, when
她想让我戴上这东西 我逃跑了
she tried to put that Fitbit on me and I ran away from her.
根据近期的一项研究
According to a recent study,
哪怕坐着不动 光是想着运动
simply thinking about exercise, even while sitting still,
也能对身体有好处
can have physical benefits.
要知道 我可能现在就在运动中
For all you know, I could be exercising right now.
- 是吗?  - 还是明天再动好了
- Are you?  - Eh, I'll do it tomorrow.
我们多运动
It wouldn't be the worst thing
也不是什么坏事
if we were more active.
你说得很对
Oh. You make an excellent point.
我都有点跑嗨了!
Ooh, I think I'm getting a runner's high!
* 宇宙一度又烫又稠密 *
* Our whole universe was in a hot, dense state *
* 140亿年前终于爆了炸... 等着瞧! *
* Then nearly 14 billion years ago expansion started... Wait! *
* 地球开始降温 *
* The Earth began to cool *
* 自养生物来起哄 穴居人发明工具 *
* The autotrophs began to drool, Neanderthals developed tools *
* 我们建长城 我们建金字塔 *
* We built the Wall We built the pyramids *
* 数学 自然科学 历史 揭开神秘 *
* Math, Science, History, unraveling the mystery *
* 一切由大爆炸开始 *
* That all started with a big bang *
生活大爆炸 第九季第5集
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 凤梨酥讨厌APA   时间轴: 奥利奥
校对: UUUUUU
翻译: 酸汤影 哎呦薇 凤梨酥 猫呗阶矩阵
看看大学开办的这些活动
Look at all these activities the university has.
攀岩俱乐部 箭术 夺旗橄榄球
Rock climbing club, archery, flag football.
我对旗帜有兴趣 对橄榄球没兴趣
Had me at flag, lost me at football.
好吧 我觉得你们想多运动是好事
Yeah, I think it's great you guys want to get more exercise,
但你们真觉得有适合你们的运动吗?
but do you really think sports is the right choice for you?
你是什么意思? 我们协调性太差
What are you saying? We're not coordinated enough
不能运动吗?
to play sports?
好吧 Leonard亲爱的
Okay, Leonard, sweetheart,
你玩拼字游戏都能扭伤脚踝
you twisted your ankle playing Scrabble.
我用两分的Q拼出了
I got a triple-word score
三倍积分的词呢 如果这时候
with a double letter "Q." If that's not a time
都不能大跳拼字游戏舞 那这舞蹈还有什么用呢?
to bust out the Scrabble dance, what's the point of having one?
嘿 Barry Kripke开了个击剑俱乐部
Hey, Barry Kripke started a fencing club.
有趣 击剑的确有某种优雅格调
Interesting. Sword fighting does hold a certain elegant appeal.
我想这个符合了我们
And I would imagine it meets many
对运动的大部分要求
of our personal criteria for a sport.
室内的 不用擦防晒霜
It's indoors, so no sunscreen.
不用丢 不用接
No throwing, no catching,
不用跑
no running.
不用穿会被拽下来的运动裤
No gym shorts that can be yanked down.
更惨的是被拽上去
Or worse, up.
说得对
Preach.
还有个额外的好处
And as an added bonus,
"一针见血"就是击剑运动里来的
the word "Touche" comes from fencing.
这是我们唯一以非隐喻性的方式
It would be our only opportunity to use it
来用到这个词
in a non-metaphorical sense.
那在法国学校玩抓人游戏的时候呢?
What about a game of tag on a French schoolyard?
touche是法国词
一针见血
Ah, touche.
谢谢你们过来
Thanks for coming by.
不客气 有什么事要我们帮忙?
Sure. So how can we help?
我知道现在比起以前
Well, I know more women are
买漫画的女人越来越多了 但出于某种原因
buying comics than ever, but for some reason,
她们... 就是不进我的店
I... I can't get 'em in here.
好吧 你都试过什么方法了?
All right, well, what have you tried so far?
我... 进了一些面向女性的漫画书
Uh, I've... I've been stocking more female-oriented titles.
我把厕所里卷纸的一头折成了
Uh, in the bathroom, I folded the end of the toilet paper
三角形
into a triangle.
还有
And, uh,
你们现在坐的地方
you are now sitting in the official
是哺乳区域
breastfeeding area.
- 不会吧? 这是漫画店诶  - 噢
- Really? In a comic book store?  - Oh,
别担心 我在这上面装了监控摄像头
don't worry. I... I've got a camera right up here,
我就能在柜台那儿看到了
so I could watch from the counter
确保没有男人在偷窥
and make sure guys aren't being pervs.
总之
Anyway,
我用什么方法
so what do I got to do to... to
能吸引你们进来?
get you in the door?
首先呢
Well, for starters,
你应该换掉某些装饰画
you might want to rethink some of this artwork.
我是说 这女人跟狗一样被绑着
I mean, this woman's actually on a leash like a dog.
你不知道这画背后的故事
Well, you don't know the backstory.
也许是因为她一直跳到沙发上呢
Maybe she kept jumping up on the couch.
我觉得好酷
I feel cool.
就像穿靴子的猫
Like Puss in Boots.
我从小就一直想
I always wanted to be a
- 成为一名剑士  - 确切来说
- swashbuckler when I was a kid.  - Technically,
"Swashbuckler"这个词包含了两部分
"Swashbuckler" is a combination of two terms.
前半部分指的是挥剑的声音
"Swash" referring to the sound of the sword.
唰
Swash.
然后
And then
后半部分指的是小型盾牌 但你没有
"Buckler" meaning a small shield, which you don't have.
我们还是可以当"唰"士呀
We can still be swashers.
说得好 小猫
Well said, Puss.
先生们 欢迎来到击剑俱乐部
Gentlemen, welcome to the fencing club.
在我们开始前 我想要提醒各位 击剑不是闹着玩
Before we start, I just want to warn you, fencing isn't a joke.
我希望你们来这里 不是因为觉得击剑会和
I hope you're not here because you think it's going to be
星战系列演的一样
like Star Wars.
我们不是为了这个来的
That's not why we're here.
没错 我来这里是因为
Yeah, I'm here because I think
觉得这会跟"权力游戏"演的一样
it's gonna be like Game of Thrones.
也许还有点像"公主新娘"演的那样
And maybe a little Princess Bride.
对了对了! 我忘了"公主新娘"!
Ooh, ooh! I forgot about Princess Bride!
我要把答案改成这个!
That's my answer!
抱歉让你们失望了 但是击剑是一项很严肃的运动
Well, sorry to disappoint you, but fencing is a serious sport.
如果你们不愿努力的话
If you're not willing to put in the effort,
最好现在就撤
you might as well just leave now.
- 我们不怵体力活动的  - 对
- We're not afraid of physical activity.  - Yeah.
我今天已经跑了29千米了
I already ran 18 miles today.
好吧 我们先学些基础的
All right. Let's begin with some fundamentals.
这是预备姿势
This is the en garde position.
双脚呈"L型" 两脚后跟在一条直线上
Feet are in an "L." Heels in a straight line.
肘关节离胸腔
Elbow is about a fist
一拳距离
from the rib cage.
注意我的主导腿面朝前方
Notice my dominant leg faces forward.
哦 不好了
Oh, dear.
怎么了 Cooper?
What's wrong, Cooper?
我不确定自己是否有主导腿
Well, I'm not sure I have a dominant leg.
它们俩都相当顺从呢
They're both pretty submissive.
你在公厕的时候
When you're in a public restroom,
通常用哪只脚冲水?
which foot do you flush the toilet with?
右脚 一直是右脚
Right. Always right.
他是个右撇子
He's a righty.
好的
Okay,
把预备姿势摆给我看
show me en garde.
好的 膝盖弯曲
Good. Knees bent,
略前于脚趾
slightly over the toe.
举起不拿剑的那只手保持平衡
Non-sword hand up for balance.
明天肯定会酸疼的
I am going to feel this tomorrow.
第一个步法叫前进
The first move is called an advance.
前脚向前 脚跟到脚趾
You move your front foot forward, heel to toe.
后脚跟上
Back foot follows.
前脚向前 脚跟到脚趾
So front foot forward, heel to toe.
后脚跟上
Back foot follows.
现在你们试试 前进
Now you try. Advance.
前进 前进
And advance. And advance.
好简单 我根本不需要穿护杯嘛
This is easy. I didn't need to wear a cup.
好的
Good.
下一个动作叫后退
The next move is called a retreat.
往后走
Step back.
后脚先动 脚趾到脚跟
Back foot first, toe to heel.
前脚跟上
Front foot follows.
我数到三
On three.
- 等等 Barry?  - 啥事
- Excuse me, Barry?  - Yes.
我什么时候能刺他们仨?
When can I stab one of my friends?
在击剑中 我们不叫刺
In fencing, we don't call it a stab.
- 我们叫击  - 呃 是的 我知道
- We call it a touch.  - Uh, yes, I'm aware.
但如果我说我想"基"我朋友的话
But if I say I want to touch one of my friends,
我会被喊进人事部的
I'll get called into Human Resources.
好的 我数到三
Okay, on three,
Cooper和Koothrappali前进 另两个后退
Cooper and Koothrappali advance, the other two retreat.
一 二 三
One, two, three.
非常好 换方向
Very good. Switch it up.
一 二 三
One, two, three.
再换方向 一 二 三
Switch again. One, two, three.
不好意思
Excuse me.
我能待会打给你吗?
Can I call you back?
不 我在上课
No, I'm teaching a class.
可以 可以
Sure. Sure.
一个小时 顶多了
An hour, tops.
是的 行
Yeah. Okay.
好的 好的
Okay. Yeah.
好的 多谢
Okay. Thanks.
来 一 二 三
And one, two, three.
你有想过直接针对女性打广告吗?
Have you thought about advertising directly to females?
嗯 行
Hmm, okay.
嗯... 好吧
Well... All right.
如果我在窗边立一个标志写上
What if I put up a sign in the window that said,
"姑娘们 进来吧
"Women, come in.
别害怕"会怎么样
Don't be afraid."
嘿
Hey.
呃 你看过网上对这地方的评论吗?
Uh, have you read the online reviews for this place?
呃
Eh,
网上评论都很负面
the Internet's so negative.
我尽量不受它们影响
I try to avoid it.
好吧 Heather H.说
All right, well, Heather H. Says,
"店主一直盯着我看
"The owner stared at me the whole time
一次眼都没眨"
and didn't blink once."
Kelly M.说
Kelly M. Says,
"那个古怪的店主约我
"The creepy guy who runs it asked me out,
又在我可以拒绝之前骂了一句自己二货"
then called himself stupid before I could say no."
Jessica K.说
Jessica K. Says,
"我跟那个诡异的店主说我喜欢他的衬衫
"I told the weird owner that I liked his shirt.
结果他就脱下来给我了"
He took it off and gave it to me."
看到了吧? 负面评价
See? Negative.
剑伸出去
With your foil extended,
前腿踢起后腿用力身体前移
kick your front leg up and push off with your back leg.
现在你们试一下
Now you try.
再来
And again.
瞧瞧 我们像火箭女郎一样
Look at us! We're like the Rockettes!
预备 Leonard
En garde, Leonard.
准备好领受一次严格的剑"基"
Prepare yourself for a rigorous touching.
公主新娘主人公
我的大名是Inigo Montoya
My name is Inigo Montoya.
你杀死了我父亲
You killed my father.
受死吧
Prepare to die.
我的大名
My name
是Inigo Montoya
is Inigo Montoya.
你杀死了我父亲 准备
You killed my father. Prepare
受死吧
to die.
我以为你是穿靴子的猫呢
I thought you were Puss in Boots.
哦 是啊 抱歉说错了
Oh, yeah, right. Sorry.
我是穿靴子的猫
My name is Puss in Boots.
你杀死了我父亲
You killed my father.
受死吧
Prepare to die.
好想让他教我们用手套打人脸的技能
I'm looking forward to him teaching us glove-slapping.
什么?
What?
就是当我的荣誉受到了侮辱
You know, when my honor is insulted,
而想跟对方决斗的时候
and I need to challenge someone to a duel
就要用手套打对方的脸
by slapping them across the face with my glove.
你的荣誉什么时候受到侮辱了?
When was your honor insulted?
上次体检的时候
My last physical.
我再说一次 那个医生没有侮辱你的荣誉
Again, that doctor didn't insult your honor.
只是前列腺检查而已
Just checked your prostate.
孤女安妮主人公
我是Little Orphan Annie
My name is Little Orphan Annie.
你杀了我父亲
You killed my father.
受死吧
Prepare to die.
星球大战
我是达斯·维达
My name is Darth Vader.
维达是天行者的父亲
我就是你父亲
I am your father.
受死吧
Prepare to die.
- 这还挺好玩的  - 真不错
- This is fun.  - Good.
你终于不再想Amy的事了
It's nice to see your mind off Amy.
Amy怎么了?
What's going on with Amy?
虽然这不关你的事
Not that it's any of your business,
不过 她和我分手了
but she broke up with me.
真的?
Really?
很高兴知道这件事
Good to know.
"很高兴"?
"Good to know"?
- 他是什么意思?  - 哦
- What's that supposed to mean?  - Oh.
我也不想让你心烦 不过看起来他好像对Amy很感兴趣啊
I hate to say it, but it sounds like he's interested in her.
这简直不能忍
Well, that's unacceptable.
嘿 哥们 你知道你对这件事有意见
Oh, buddy, I get that you don't like it,
但是这也不是你能控制得了的
but it's not really up to you.
说得对 可是他也太蠢了 长得还丑
Yeah, but he's dumb, and his face is dumb.
就算不是他
Look, even if it's not him,
Amy也迟早会开始和别人约会的
Amy's probably going to date someone at some point.
你真这么觉得?
You really think so?
当然了 她有权利过得开心啊
Of course. She deserves to be happy.
你竟然这么想!
How dare you!
我觉得我应该给你个忠告
Listen, I should warn you
约Amy出去可能不太明智
that maybe asking Amy out isn't a good idea.
Barry 能跟你说句话吗?
Barry, a word?
你将听到的就是刚刚这话的暴走版
And now the crazy version of what I just said.
你要是想追Amy的话
If you intend to pursue Amy,
我就别无选择 只能想办法让你住手了
you leave me with no choice but to put a stop to it.
你想怎样?
And how are you gonna do that?
跟你决斗
By challenging you to a duel.
你只上过一次课 我会完爆你的
You've had one lesson. I'll destroy you.
所以 决斗会在从今天起三年后
That is why the duel will take place
的那天正午举行
at high noon, three years from today.
如果你能够担任击剑教练的话
If you're worth your salt as an instructor,
三年之后 我应该也差不多了
I should be ready by then.
还有 我警告你
Yeah, and be warned.
到时候 我会"基"遍你全身的
I'm going to touch you all over.
哇哦 这... 这比我想的还要暴走
Wow. That... that was crazier than I thought.
好吧 虽然可能不是真的
All right, I'm not saying
我们... 我们可以先假设
it's true, but let's... let's consider for a moment
- 有可能 是我自己身上出了问题  - 好啊
- that possibly I'm the problem.  - Yeah.
- 太对了  - 就是这么回事
- You are.  - You can say it.
好吧 好吧 那...?
Okay, fine. What...?
我能做什么啊?
I mean, what can I do?
在女人面前我就是会特别紧张
I get so nervous around women.
你正跟我们说话呢
Well, you're talking to us now.
看起来 你也没有很紧张啊
I mean, you don't seem nervous.
那是因为我说话的时候在假想
Well, that's because I'm doing that trick
听众都没穿衣服之类的
where you imagine the audience is naked.
对了 你们身材都不错呢
By the way, thumbs up, ladies.
你自己知道这听起来有多诡异吗?
Do you not hear how creepy that sounds?
我开玩笑的
It was a joke.
是吗?
Was it?
不是 我还是在这么想
No, I'm still doing it.
好吧
Okay.
我无意冒犯 但是...
Don't be offended, but...
你到底有什么毛病啊?
what went wrong with you?
我... 我想我只是觉得
I... I guess I assumed at this point in my life,
现在我应该已经恋爱或者结婚
I would be married or in a relationship,
或者有一只
or even have a pet
不会跑出去自杀的宠物也好啊
that didn't run away or kill itself.
真的有宠物会自杀?
That really happened?
我也不确定 不过我发誓
I mean, I can't say for sure, but I swear
我的兔子在冲到一辆车下面之前
that rabbit looked me right in the eye
绝对看了我一眼
before it hopped in front of that car.
好吧
Anyway,
我孤单一人的时间越长 就越绝望
the longer I'm alone, the more desperate I get.
Stuart 不管你相不相信 我能理解你的心情
Stuart, believe it or not, I understand.
在我认识Sheldon之前
You know, before I met Sheldon,
有很长时间我都生活在孤独中
I was alone for a really long time.
那时候的我
I was so desperate
太希望别人喜欢我了 当我认识她们的时候
for people to like me, when I met these guys,
我尽了最大的努力 来掩饰自己缺乏安全感的事实
it took everything in my power to hide my insecurity.
我们其实都感觉到了
Okay, we're all feeling it.
好啦 我约你出去
Yes, I'll go out with you.
我好像突然理解那只兔子了
Suddenly, the rabbit thing makes sense.
Sheldon 我真没想到你居然愿意来体育主题的酒吧
I'm surprised you wanted to go to a sports bar, Sheldon.
你看这水泡
Look at this blister.
不管喜不喜欢 我们已经是运动员了
Like it or not, we're athletes now.
而且 在我想不明白感情问题的时候
Besides, a bar is where I belong.
我就会来酒吧
I'm having female problems.
你要是感觉心情不太好 还想酗酒的话 我倒是知道为什么
If you're cranky and retaining water, I have a theory.
Sheldon 别再想着Amy和别人约会的事了
Sheldon, instead of focusing on Amy dating other guys,
还不如考虑考虑约别的女孩出去
maybe you should start thinking about dating another girl.
别开玩笑了
That's ridiculous.
怎么了? 在遇到Amy之前
Why? You never thought
你不是也没想过恋爱吗
you'd end up in a relationship,
结果你遇到了Amy
and then you met Amy.
也许还有其他的另一半在等着你
Maybe there's someone else out there for you.
有道理 但是Penny和Bernadette都结婚了
True, but Penny's married, and so is Bernadette.
而你的女朋友长着红头发白皮肤
And your girlfriend has red hair and white skin,
这会勾起我的小丑恐惧症
which really rubs up against my clown phobia.
也许你可以把
Maybe you should consider women
你好朋友认真谈的对象
who aren't in serious relationships
排除在外?
with your closest friends?
有一个前列腺医生 但是我还在生她的气
There's that prostate doctor, but I'm still mad at her.
哎 那里有个女人
Oh, there's a woman.
我让她来当我女朋友
Oh, I'll make her my girlfriend.
等等
Whoa, whoa.
在酒吧里随便跑到陌生女人面前不会起作用的
Walking up to a strange woman in a bar usually doesn't work.
你忘记一件事了
You're forgetting something.
姑娘们都爱运动员
Ladies love jocks.
他刚喝了几口啤酒?
How many sips of that beer did he have?
- 三口  - 大事不妙
- Three.  - Oh, boy.
打扰一下 我现在处于分手恢复期
Excuse me. I'm recovering from a recent breakup,
和其他女人约会可能会让我好受一点
and I'm told asking out another woman might make me feel better.
所以就像小智对皮卡丘说的 "我选你了"
And as Ash Ketchum said to Pikachu, "I choose you."
什么?
What?
这是宠物小精灵的梗
It's a Pokemon reference.
我听不懂这是什么意思
I don't know what that means.
好吧 至少咱们试过了
Well, we gave it a shot.
你怎么样?
How about you?
我结婚了 而且我是她的奶奶
I'm married, and I'm her grandmother.
你咋没早点遇到朕
Ah, what might have been.
还有你 替我向马戏团问好
And you, give my regards to Barnum and Bailey.
Barnum and Bailey美国一家马戏团公司
Stuart对她的的拒绝 接受的还挺好的
Stuart took that rejection like a pro.
因为他知道咪咪摄像头正对着他呢
Well, he knew he was on the breast cam.
我没有拒绝他人的经验
I don't have much practice turning men down.
太没意思了
It wasn't so much fun.
哦 你会习惯的
Oh, you get used to it.
有些人你要拒绝一次又一次
Some guys you have to turn down over and over.
有时候你最后还是嫁给他了
And sometimes we marry them anyway.
哈
Huh.
真是奇怪
Well, this is weird.
- 怎么了?  - Barry Kripke约我了
- What?  - Barry Kripke just asked me out.
哦
Oh.
看看你呀... 一天有两个男人向你示好!
Look at you... two guys in one day!
我就说把你的眉毛修修能带来桃花运吧!
I told you things would change if you plucked your eyebrows!
他怎么说的?
What did he say?
"嗨 你好吗? 我在想
"Hi, how are you? I was wondering
你愿不愿意有空和我一起喝点什么"
if you'd like to get a drink after work sometime."
那你准备怎么办?
Well, what are you gonna do?
我不知道
I don't know.
我本来想 我以后会和别人去约会的
I guess I assumed that I would eventually date other people,
但是这一切来得太快了
but this is happening so fast.
有什么坏处吗?
What can it hurt?
我希望下一个和我约会的人
Well, I was hoping the next person I dated
不要那么像Sheldon
would be a little less like Sheldon.
你是说 不要是个科学家?
You mean, not a scientist?
我觉得她是说 不要是个怪胎
I think she means not a weirdo.
你对他有意思吗?
Are you attracted to him?
我不知道
I don't know.
好吧 那你想象一下他的裸体 会有什么反应?
All right, well, what happens if you imagine him naked?
哦 根本不需要想
Oh, I don't have to imagine it.
我闻起来怪怪的
I smell funny.
舔起来咸咸的
I taste salty.
你只是锻炼之后出汗了而已
You're just sweaty from exercise.
尝起来还挺好吃的
And kind of delicious.
不知道要舔几下才能舔到我的夹心呢
I wonder how many licks it would take to get to the center of me.
我知道只要医生的一根手指就可以
I know it only takes one doctor's finger.
哈喽
Hello.
应该让你们单独聊聊
We should let you guys talk.
说得对
Yeah.
你不需要走开的
You don't have to leave.
你来追我呀!
Look at me go!
呃 Bernadette你说好开车带我的
Uh, Bernadette, you're my ride.
走回去!
Walk!
你怎么样了?
How have you been?
我挺好的
I'm doing all right.
我今天去练习击剑了
I tried fencing today.
练的怎么样了?
How'd that go?
挺简单的
It was pretty easy.
我想是我"运算员"的背景给了很大的帮助
And I think my background in "Mathletics" helped.
Barry Kripke也在那
Barry Kripke was there.
我要告诉你
I should let you know
他有兴趣约你
that he expressed interest in asking you out.
实际上 他... 已经约了
Well, actually, he... he already did.
好吧
Okay.
但是别喜欢上他
But don't get too attached to him.
因为两年又364天之后 他就死了
In two years, 364 days, he's a dead man.
我拒绝了
I said no.
有意思
Interesting.
我今天约了两个女人出门 她们也都拒绝了我
I asked two women out today, and they both said no.
想不到你对约会有兴趣
I didn't know you were interested in dating.
有人告诉我这是重新开始的好办法
I've been told it's a good way to move on.
哦
Oh.
好吧
Okay.
不管怎样 呃 很高兴能看到你
Anyway, um, it's nice to see you.
你看起来挺好的
You look good.
嗯 谢谢
Mmm, thanks.
我尝起来也挺好的
And I taste good too.
Howie啊?
Howie?
怎么了?
What's up?
为什么你的Fitbit上显示你昨天跑了280千米?
Why does your Fitbit say you ran 174 miles yesterday?